stepchange.org 2017-06-06

# Privacy & Cookie Policy. StepChange Debt Charity

We are committed to respecting and protecting your privacy.

The structure of the Site is such that you can browse any area within it, StepChange Debt Remedy in particular, without revealing who you are or any other personal information about you.

## Personal details

If you do elect to follow the advice offered in StepChange Debt Remedy, your personal details will be required to enable us to contact you. Your consent will be required before you proceed. We will keep all your personal information confidential and secure and we will only use this data to provide you with the services requested.

While visiting our Site, and in particular when accepting the debt advice provided by Debt Remedy, you may voluntarily choose to provide your email address. This information will only be used for the purpose of providing you with the specific information requested by you, or to send you important updates concerning our debt advice or the debt solution you may have chosen. Should you not select a debt solution following a Debt Remedy session, your email address will be deleted after 6 months. It will not be passed to any other organisation.

You may also choose to provide your email address (on our website, during telephone calls with us, or via other recognised means of providing us consent to communicate with you) as a means of signing up to receive StepChange Debt Charity emails and newsletters.

The privacy policy relating to our use of your email address for this purpose can be found here. 

## Security

If you decide to use the StepChange Debt Remedy service, you will be provided with a web number to enable you to re-enter the Site at your convenience.  You must take reasonable precautions to prevent the unauthorised use of your web number.

You should not record or disclose your web number in any way that may result in it becoming known to another person. This could lead to your financial details being accessed and used in an unauthorised manner.

You will be responsible for the accuracy of information transmitted by you and received by us between the time that you access the Site until you log off and exit it. Please note that this includes any input errors or instructions sent by anyone else, with or without your consent. Please do not therefore, leave the device you are using unattended while you are logged on to the Site.

## Cookies

Cookies are small data files that are sent to your browser. We use these to collect anonymous information about your use of the Site. Unless you have specifically set your browser not to receive cookies, your browser will automatically accept them. No personal data is collected from them.

Cookies can be deleted from your computer and if you wish you may set your browser not to receive cookies in future. For more information on how to control cookies on your machine, read this guide.

<http://www.aboutcookies.org/>

The information that the cookies collect is used to monitor the usage and measure the performance of the service that the Site offers.

Other than the StepChange Debt Remedy option, acceptance or rejection of cookies does not affect your ability to use this Site. Use of StepChange Debt Remedy requires acceptance of cookies. No personal data is collected from you unless you specifically provide us with that information.

### We use the following cookies on our sites and services:

Cookie | Name | Purpose | Where are these used?  
---|---|---|---  
Google Analytics | __utma  
__utmz  
__utmc  
__utmb  
__utmx  
__utmxx | These cookies are used to collect information about how our visitors use our website. This information includes the number of visitors to the website, which website they came from and which pages they looked at on our website. The cookies collect information anonymously. | The main website, Debt Remedy, jobs website and Wellbeing  
Webtrends | ACOOKIE  
WT_FPC | These cookies are used to collect information about how our visitors use our website. This information includes the number of visitors to the website, which website they came from and which pages they looked at on our website. The cookies collect information anonymously. | The main website, Debt Remedy, jobs website, Online DMP and Wellbeing  
YouTube | VISITOR_INFO1_LIVE  
PREF  
use_hitbox | These cookies are used in the video functionality of a YouTube embedded video. | The main website  
ASP.NET | .ASPXANONYMOUS  
ASP.NET_SessionId  
ASPXAUTH  
RequestVerificationToken_Lw | These cookies help the functionality of the website. These are deleted when you close your browser. | The main website, Debt Remedy, Online DMP, jobs website and Wellbeing  
DotNetNuke | language | This cookie helps the functionality of the website. This is deleted when you close your browser. | The main website  
Live Chat | JSESSIONID | This cookie helps the functionality of the Live Chat tool if the user needs help with debt advice or with completing Debt Remedy. This is deleted when you close your browser. | The main website and Debt Remedy  
PDF Generator | ysm_bbk159O43…. | This cookie helps automatically generate a PDF information booklet at the end of Debt Remedy. This is deleted when you close your browser. | Debt Remedy  
QuestionPro | Survey  
siteRef | This cookie is set when you use the survey at the end of Debt Remedy, to aid its functionality. It does not collect any identifiable information. | The main website  
Yahoo/Bing | B  
BX | This cookie is set if you visit Debt Remedy from a pay-per-click advert in the Yahoo.co.uk search results. It does not collect any identifiable information. | Debt Remedy  
Google | test_cookie | This cookie is set if you visit Debt Remedy from a pay-per-click advert in the Google.co.uk search results. It does not collect any identifiable information. | Debt Remedy  
DoubleClick | id  
test_cookie | We use Google Analytics and DoubleClick cookies and remarketing services to log when someone views a specific page or takes a specific action on our websites. This allows us to provide targeted information in the future, in the form of an advertisement on Google’s search results page. Of course, any data collected is used in accordance with our own privacy policy and Google’s privacy policy.* | The main website, Debt Remedy, Online DMP, jobs website and Wellbeing  
Jobs website | ccp_name4697  
ccp_user4697  
lastaccesstime4697  
sessionid4697  
wedeputy_reg_email_5699  
wedeputy_reg_username_5699< | These cookies are used to track details of applicants using our jobs website. | Jobs website  
Atlas | ATN | This cookie logs when you view a specific page or takes a specific action on our websites. This allows us to provide targeted information in the future, in the form of an advertisement. | The main website, Debt Remedy, Online DMP, jobs website and Wellbeing  
Device Atlas | DAPROPS | This cookie is used to track the activity during the visit for analytical purposes to improve the service. | The main website  
Cookie policy | StepChange_AcceptCookiePolicy  
cookillian_opt_in  | These cookies lets us know your cookie preferences when you're on our site. | The main website  
Anti-forgery | __RequestVerificationToken_Lw__ | This cookie is associated with a particular anti-forgery method to prevent cross site request forgery in user forms. | Online DMP  
Mobile detection | dnn_IsMobile | This cookie helps us know whether you're on a mobile device | The main website  
Site preference | StepChangeSitePref | This cookie tracks whether you prefer the desktop or mobile version of our site | The main website  
  
*If you do not wish to receive this type of service from us you can opt-out of Google's use of cookies by visiting Google's [ Ad Preferences page](http://www.google.com/settings/ads/onweb/) or the [Network Advertising Initiative opt-out page](http://www.networkadvertising.org/managing/opt_out.asp).

The companies who collect information on our websites may combine this with other information they’ve independently collected from other websites and/or other online or mobile products and services relating to your activities across their network of websites.  Many of these companies collect and use information under their own privacy policies.

## Usage

The Site is intended for non-commercial personal use only and is provided for the exclusive use of private individuals requiring debt advice. Interference or entry to the Site with intent to corrupt, damage or deny service from the Site or for commercial benefit is taken seriously and we will take such action as is necessary to protect the Site from any such activities. The Site and the elements of it are the property of StepChange Debt Charity. You are not allowed to modify or alter any material provided on the Site in any way.
